# **Samuel Gemberling**

Dallas, Texas • <a href="mailto:sgemberling@gmail.com">sgemberling@gmail.com</a> • 469-556-5475 sgemberling.dev • <a href="mailto:github.com/sgemberling117">github.com/sgemberling117</a>

## **Summary**

I am a very inquisitive and disciplined web developer, during my 11 years in various martial arts I learned that I will never know everything, so I am excited to learn anything! From something as large as a different way somebody approaches their coding process to something as small as a nuanced edge case. I take pride in how hard I work and I love creating tools to make other people's lives easier.

## **Projects**

Restaurants Around the World: https://restaurants-atw.herokuapp.com

GitHub: https://github.com/sgemberling117/restaurants

- Role: Full-Stack Developer (solo project)
- Developed a full stack application where users can search for and save their favorite restaurants from anywhere in the world
- Utilized MERN Stack (MongoDB/mongoose, Express, React, Node), CSS, JWT Authentication, Git/GitHub, Heroku, Google Places API

Cinque: <a href="http://cinque.cinquewd.com/">http://cinque.cinquewd.com/</a>

GitHub: https://github.com/Cinque-Web-Development/cinque

- Role: Front end developer (team project)
- Integrated multiple APIs into a single web page
- Utilized: React, CSS, Calendarific API, SportsDB API, DataNews API, Open Weather Map API, NASA APOD API, Twitter API, Reddit API, Netlify, Progressive Web App (PWA), Git and GitHub

JWT Auth Template with MySQL: https://jwt-template-mysql.herokuapp.com

GitHub: https://github.com/sgemberling117/jwt-auth-template-with-mysgl

- Role: Full-Stack Developer (solo project)
- Created template for people wanting to start a MySQL React project without worrying about the authentication
- Utilized SERN Stack (SQL/MySQL, Express, React, Node), CSS, JWT Authentication, Git/GitHub, Heroku, ClearDB(for deployment)

### **Technical Skills**

**Proficient**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, mongoose, MySQL, PostgreSQL, React, Mac Command Line, Responsive Web Design, OAuth, Agile, Heroku, REST APIs, Relational Databases, Document-Based Databases, Postman, JSON, iQuery, Git/GitHub, AJAX

Experienced: C++, C#, Python, Django, Gatsby, Sass, Netlify, Materialize, BootStrap, graphQL, Markdown

## **Experience**

Dialexa, Dallas, TX - Software Engineer

September 2021 - Present

### Cinque Web Development, Dallas, TX - Full-Stack Developer

August 2020 - September 2021

- Develops applications with a distributed team to meet clients' business needs and personal goals
- Responsible for primarily back end development, working in React, Node, and JavaScript

### General Assembly, Dallas, TX - Teaching Assistant

August 2020 - September 2021

- Assisted students with homework and taught them skills to analyze problems and arrive at solutions
- Inspire and support students as they identify their passions and drive their own continued learning beyond the curriculum

#### Education

Certificate in Software Engineering - General Assembly, Dallas, TX

April 2020 - July 2020